Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Altitude 2,400. Speed 28,000. Relative to Earth.
Leaving Earth atmosphere. Switching to space speed 2.
Can we really save Earth?
Getting cold feet, Tactical Officer?
It's not like that...
Ship off our starboard bow. It's a friendly.
"We pray for your safe journey."
We will now pass through lunar orbit, and head for Mars, at cruising speed.
Upon arrival, main staff are to gather in the central operations room.
There will be a briefing on the warp test. That is all.
This is the impact observation team. A Teron ship has left orbit.
Should we send the fleet?
No, let's see what it does.
What does an inferior race, who cannot even leave their own solar system,
plan to do with a single ship?
I'd like to watch and find out.
Men, the journey to Iscandar and back would take 336,000 years, at light speed.
And we must complete that voyage within a single year.
To do this, we require faster-than-light warp navigation,
capable of breaking the light barrier.
A warp functions by generating an artificial wormhole,
that allows travel beyond the speed of light.
I don't fully understand this, but is it even possible?
Theoretically, yes.
But if you botch the timing, you'll create a space-time continuum distortion,
and phase transition the universe itself.
Meaning what, in practice?
That we must be very careful with the Wave Motion Engine.
Getting cold feet, Navigation Officer?
It's not like that.
And one more thing.
I am Niimi, the Engineering Intelligence Officer.
We have completed a weapon, capable of harnessing the Wave Motion Engine's
vast power, and have loaded it aboard the Yamato's bow.
A weapon?
The Dimensional Wave Motion Explosive Compression Emitter.
We call it the Wave Motion Gun for short.
The Wave Motion Gun? How does it work?
Put simply,
it extends the higher dimensions,
expanded in the Wave Motion Engine, along its line of fire.
The micro black holes created by super gravity
release Hawking radiation.
So does that mean the entire ship is a giant cannon?
Not quite, but close.
I don't understand at all.
Eventually, we'll need to test fire the Wave Motion Gun.
We'll test the warp in the low gravity interference area past Mars.
The test is set for 0130. Everyone, suit up, just in case.
Dismissed!
Sasha is asleep on Mars, isn't she?
All alone...
Please watch us. We will reach your homeland.
After a journey to Earth, of 168,000 light years, all alone.
A journey too long to even imagine...
You gave us the courage and hope to survive. We won't let that go to waste...
Chief, can we really bend space-time itself?
No idea! Sometimes, you've just gotta try.
Two minutes until test.
Confirm post-warp coordinates.
Confirmed.
Point S8630, in Uranus's orbit. Coordinate axis set.
Increasing speed, from 12 to 33 s-knots.
Increase engine output.
Raise output from 40 to 99.
Wave Motion Engine internal pressure rising.
Speed is 30 s-knots...
33 s-knots!
One minute until test.
The ship sets sail, and the smoke stays behind.
The smoke that stays behind causes the throat to ache.
There we go! It's time!
Even if he does come from a family of priests, that chant is still pretty morbid.
Speed is 36 s-knots!
Commencing countdown.
10...
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Warp!
Yes!
Where are we?
Jupiter...
Why?
Hey, Shima!
Navigation Officer, report!
I-I don't know...
The space-time coordinates were right...
An unknown obstacle was detected in our path.
It may have been an attempt to avoid it.
The Yamato is caught in Jupiter's gravity field!
It's no good. It's drawing us in...
I can't control the ship!
Stay calm!
Engine room, report.
The main engine isn't transferring energy correctly.
I'll try switching to sub-engines.
Power flowing to the sub-engines.
Deploying stabilizer wings.
Take care of it, Shima.
I know!
I'm seeing something on radar. 65,000 kilometers away.
Not a ship. It's too big!
Magnify.
Switching to infrared.
That's...
That floating object is nearly the size of Australia.
Shima, soft land the Yamato on the floating continent.
Roger!
Shima, almost there!
Fire anchor!
Fire!
Captain, we've located the cause of the engine trouble.
The main engine's coolant system is overheating.
Understood.
Begin repairs immediately.
Kodai, put a team together from the deck crew, and go collect samples.
Yes, sir!
AU09, it's your turn to shine.
Don't call me by number.
I am a free unit.
This thing is autonomous?
AU09, the Yamato's autonomous sub-computer.
Call me Analyzer.
Daddy, finish your work soon, and come home, okay?
Mom's worried...
Commander Shultz...
What is it, Ganz?
A message from Larleta, at the Floating Continent base.
From planet five, Zupist?
Yes. The Teron ship has landed there.
Ridiculous...
It should still be wandering the inner solar system.
Well, apparently, they have also seen traces of a Geschtam Jump.
Impossible.
Are you trying to tell me they jumped?
I couldn't say for certain...
What of the Floating Continent's fleet?
It's a resupply base. Presently, only four ships are there.
That will be sufficient.
Have Larleta use those ships to destroy them.
Yes, sir.
Understood.
I shall dispatch the combat fleet immediately.
Teron weapons cannot pierce our armor.
Four is practically overkill.
Hunting for plants... Feels like I'm back in elementary school.
Stop whining.
Temperature and pressure are far different than on Jupiter's surface.
Atmospheric composition: Methane 67%..
Nitrogen 6%. Carbon dioxide 21%.
Detecting acetaldehyde and ethanol, as well.
Alcohol, huh?
Come to think of it, I'm kinda...
Warp sickness, huh?
What's that?
Like a hangover.
Want a drink, to dull the pain?
I'll pass...
DNA match with unknown, extraterrestrial plants now living on Earth is 99.98%.
In other words, this environment was imported, from outside the solar system.
They moved this entire continent to Jupiter, to aid in gamilasforming Earth.
Then there should be...
Ships on radar!
Gamilas vessels.
All crew to battle stations!
Prepare to fire main guns.
But, Kodai, until the main engine is fixed, we can't route energy to the guns!
The Type-3 rounds are bullets. We can fire them.
The Type-3 are for short range!
If we had shock cannons, we could shoot them from a distance.
Captain, we could use a bypass to fire a few rounds from the shock cannons.
The repairs will be done in five minutes. Can you hold out that long?
There's no time. Connect the bypass.
Route power to main guns.
Ready Type-3 artillery in secondary guns!
Energy transferred to main guns. We can fire shock cannons!
One and two, aim for the destroyers approaching on port side.
Three, prepare to fire at the ship circling around from aft.
Target locked. Auto-tracking enabled.
Open fire!
Torpedoes approaching from port!
AA defenses!
Enemy torpedoes downed!
Enemy ships now within range of Type-3 rounds!
Secondary guns, open fire.
Fire!
Enemy ship in retreat.
This is the engine room. Repairs complete.
Activate engine. Raise anchor!
We're reaching the continent's edge!
We're 23,000 kilometers from the floating continent!
Kodai, fire the Wave Motion Gun at the floating continent.
We will test fire the Wave Motion Gun,
and destroy the enemy base.
We don't know how powerful the Wave Motion Gun is.
Without knowing possible effects, using it will be too risky.
Let's try it, Sanada.
If we can't do it here, we won't be able to test it anywhere.
All crew, stand by to open fire.
Turn the ship around. Point bow at the floating continent.
Switching ship to emergency power, in preparation for reboot.
Navigation Officer, transfer control to Tactical Officer.
Transferring to Tactical Officer.
Tactical Officer has control.
Mori, what heat sources are visible on the continent?
They're concentrated in the basin, at the continent's center.
Send the coordinates... Kodai!
Roger! Pointing bow at continent's center.
Open circuit to the Wave Motion Gun.
Opening circuit.
Sealing emergency vents. Activating force injector.
Release safety lock.
Releasing safety lock.
Confirmed activation of force injector. Final safety released.
Target scope open!
Tachyon particle pressure rising in chamber.
86, 97, 100...
Energy charge at 120%.
Floating continent is 23,000 kilometers off the bow. Relative speed 36.
Bow is level with firing axis.
Correct for target errors +2 degrees.
Prepare to fire Wave Motion Gun.
Engage anti-shock and anti-flare defenses.
Electronic cross-gauge, display brightness twenty. Target locked.
Ten seconds until fire.
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Fire.
What is this?
What in the world is happening?
This is the Wave Motion Gun...
An amazing weapon!
With this, we can fight the Gamilans on even terms...
No, we have the advantage!
However, we only wanted to destroy the Gamilas base.
But the Wave Motion Gun destroyed the entire continent.
Our objective isn't to exterminate the enemy.
The Yamato's weaponry exists solely for self-defense.
A power that could destroy the universe itself.
Have we attained the forbidden fire of Megiddo?
No, I won't think of that now.
If this is a trial, we need only show the correct path in our actions.
Episode 3
Escape from the Jupiter Sphere
The unknown calls to us
Does your courage burn to go there?
We rush on a journey
For everyone to survive together
For happiness
Though there is pain
And sadness
We will not be defeated
Those who know the beautiful Earth
Restore its wonders
Bring it back, bring it back
The road to tomorrow
Not afraid anymore
Determined to reach our destination
The Wave Motion Gun...
Its terrifying power has damaged the Yamato itself.
A mysterious distress call...
Different feelings...
What will the man of the sea decide?
And Kodai sees a hero, who rests upon a frozen satellite.
A requiem sounds in empty space.
Next time: Gravestone on a Frozen Field.
There are 363 days left before humanity is extinct.